figureprints.com 2018-12-23

# FigurePrints - Privacy Policy

FigurePrints® Privacy Policy 

FigurePrints® takes your privacy very seriously. This Privacy Policy describes how FigurePrints® uses identifiable information regarding our customers, such as name, address, email address or credit card number (“Customer Information”). Primarily, we collect such information for the purpose of providing you with an outstanding experience with the Site and the Service. Except as specifically described in this Privacy Policy, FigurePrints® does not sell, rent or share such Customer Information with third parties. 

By using the Service, you consent to the collection and use of information in the manner described below. If we decide to change our privacy practice, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it. Changes to our policy will be prospective only. Please check this page from time to time for changes to make sure you are aware of our latest privacy practices. 

What Customer Information does FigurePrints® collect? 

Customer Information is requested whenever you choose to use the Services. When you upload material to and order a product from the Site and the Service, we will require your first and last name, phone number, email address, and shipping and billing information so that we can fulfill your request.  

How does FigurePrints® use Customer Information? 

Our primary goal in collecting your Customer Information is to fulfill your order and deliver your product to you. When you order a product from us, we may ask if you would like us to store your billing and shipping information under a personalized account. If you choose to do so, you won’t have to fill out the shipping and billing address each and every time you purchase. We reserve the right to use aggregated, anonymous data about our users as a group. For example, we might give certain demographic information about our customers to prospective advertisers. Your Customer Information, however, will never be personally identifiable when aggregated for these purposes. 

With whom does FigurePrints® share Customer Information? 

FigurePrints® may share Customer Information with third party intermediaries (for example, PayPal, credit card authorization companies, vendors processing our outbound email communication, etc.) who help us run the Site and the Service. Your Customer Information is provided to these third parties solely for the purpose of providing you the services you request at the time that you request them. Third party intermediaries do not store, retain, access or otherwise use your Customer Information other than as necessary to provide you with the Service. Other than as described in the previous paragraphs, FigurePrints® will not sell, rent or otherwise share Customer Information with a third party without your knowledge and consent. If you do not want your Customer Information shared at that time you will always have the option of telling us not to share it. The one exception to the rule described in this section is the following: if FigurePrints® is required by law (or to protect its rights or property), we will disclose Customer Information to the extent so required. 

Who sees your material after it has been submitted to the Service? 

Visitors or users of the Site will not have access to your material once it has been submitted to FigurePrints®. FigurePrints® employees or employees of partner companies that provide services to FigurePrints® may see your material while it is being printed, packaged and shipped. In addition, your submitted materials or Customer Information may be seen by FigurePrints® employees in order to evaluate, validate, or correct problems with your order. 

Does FigurePrints® use IP Addresses and cookies? 

FigurePrints® may use IP Addresses and Cookies in limited ways, as follows:

 _IP Addresses:_

An IP address is your computer’s address and is a unique identifier, allowing online information to be sent to the right place. We may use IP addresses to better understand who our customers are. We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. Your IP address may also be used to gather broad demographic information such as the geographic distribution of our customers. We do not intentionally link your IP address to your personally identifiable information.

 _Cookies:_

The purpose of a cookie is to record only information you volunteer to us upon visiting the Site. Cookies are tiny files placed onto the hard drive of your computer the first time that you visit our Site, and enable our server to recognize or “remember” who you are for subsequent visits to the Site. FigurePrints® cookies are not tied to personally identifiable information. FigurePrints® may make limited use of cookies for the purpose of delivering content and ads specific to your interests. For instance cookies may be used to retain your personal preferences or hold session information for a “shopping cart.”

 _Advertiser Cookies:_

FigurePrints® may post third party advertising banners. These ads may contain cookies used primarily to provide data to the advertiser about where visitors are coming from. While we may use cookies in other parts of our Site as explained above, cookies received with banner ads may or may not be collected or controlled by us. When you click on a banner ad, you should be aware that the advertiser might be collecting information without the permission of FigurePrints®. FigurePrints® does not control the privacy practices of any advertisers.

 _Advice on Limiting Cookies:_

You always have a choice with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you can accept all cookies, be notified when a cookie is set, or reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies, you may be unable to use certain FigurePrints® services. Please consult your browser instructions for information on how to modify your choices about cookies.   

What are the safeguards and security procedures in place to protect your information from loss, misuse, or alteration? 

If you are using a public computer (public library, school computer, etc.) or a shared computer (family computer, roommate’s computer, etc.), we strongly recommend that you close your browser and delete any cookies before getting up and moving away from the computer. This will prevent others from accessing your personal information. Please note that because our company is particularly sensitive to protecting information about children on the Internet, kids under 13 are not eligible to visit or use the Site or the Services. However, we encourage parents to use our service as a family activity with their children and to carefully monitor any Internet activities (including use of the FigurePrints® Site and Services) engaged in by their kids. FigurePrints® employs SSL - a specialized encryption and security technology -- to protect your Customer Information. We understand that this is especially important when there is an exchange of credit card, billing and password information. In addition, we limit access of Customer Information to only those employees who need it to carry out their jobs. FigurePrints® will never ask you for your Customer Information in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email. You will only be asked for your Customer Information when you initiate the contact and only if such information is necessary to correct a service problem. 

If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner that is materially different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you via email. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on the Site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post the notice, we will also email users who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices. 

Does FigurePrints® guarantee that advertisers will follow these same policies? 

If you click away from FigurePrints® to visit the site of any third party advertiser or sponsor, you may be asked for your credit card or other personal information in order to purchase or use products and services offered. These companies have their own privacy and data collection practices. FigurePrints® has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. You should therefore review their privacy policies carefully if you have concerns about how your information may be used.
